ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
煮粥达人
翻译
showeryhe
木浅
翻译
潇湘月影
某羽
时间轴
Kallen   youliss
特效
宝宝  草草
电脑狂人
第二季
第九集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
我们银行里大概有六千美元
So, we've got about six grand in the bank.
不够我们自己另找网络
It's not enough to fund our own network,
但如果我们再拖一次工资
but if we skip payroll again...
不行  程序员都累坏了
No, we can't. The coders are burnt.
我们得定好计划回去见他们
We have to go back to them with a plan.
那我们大多数用户醒来后登录
So most of our users are gonna wake up, log on,
会奇怪我们为什么把名字改成了西方网络
and wonder why we changed our name to WestNet.
我知道你想把乔绑在铁轨上  我也想
Look, I know you want to strap Joe to a rail and so do I...
先不考虑他
He's not a priority.
好吧  我们现在只有
Okay, so, all we've really got at this point
一屋子的康懋达64
is a house full of commodore 64s,
-XT  家具  -还有我们的游戏
- the XTs, the furniture... - and our games.
这是唯一没被他们偷走的东西  对吗
I mean, that's the only thing they didn't steal, right?
《营救保卫战》是我们最新的游戏
"Extract & Defend" is our freshest title.
它应该能卖个好价钱让我们维持下去
I think it can fetch enough to keep us afloat.
你真要那样吗  你要卖吗
You would do that? You would sell?
唐娜  这是为了生存
Donna, this is about survival.
试探一下雪乐山游戏
Put out some feelers to Sierra on-line,
卡带机市场  我会联络独立游戏制作团体
the cartridge market, I'll reach out to the independents.
西方网络呢  可惜我们不能告他们
What about WestNet? It's too bad we can't sue 'em.
该你了
Your turn.
喂
Yeah?
你开玩笑吧  哪里
You gotta be kidding me. Which... I mean, where?
嗯  我知道那个
Yeah, I know the one.
天啊  戈登  闭嘴等着
For god's sakes, Gordon, you can shut up and wait.
他想怎样
What does he even want?
让我去监狱接他回家
A ride home from jail.
-你还需要别的吗  -不用  我自己来
- You need anything else? - Nah, I'll make it.
谢谢
Thanks.
直接回家  戈登
Go straight home, Gordon.
梳洗一下
Clean yourself up.
坐上飞机
Get on that damn plane.
把这些都抛在身后
Put all this behind you.
JGL定制电脑德州  达拉斯  西克诺索斯大街417
我刚听到的是真的吗
Is it true, what I just heard?
大概吧
Uh, probably.
你要卖掉
That you're selling
我们这四个月的心血吗
what we've just spent the last four months of our lives on?
我别无选择  汤姆
It's not like I have much of a choice, Tom.
好  我们能先缓缓吗
Okay, can we just... can we just take it slow for a second?
是啊  我倒希望我可以
yes, I really wish I had that luxury.
我只是不希望你这么草率  好吗
I just don't want you to act too hastily, okay?
或者说  惊慌
Or... or... or panic.
你能不能...我心里有数的
Can you... I know what I'm doing.
好吧  你本打算什么时候告诉我
Well, at what point were you gonna tell me?
写游戏的这个人
You know, the guy who wrote the game.
-合作写的  -我们现在还斤斤计较了吗
- Cowrote it. - Oh, we're splitting hairs now.
汤姆
Tom.
我累了  好吗
I'm tired, okay?
我身上一股火药和啤酒味
I smell like gunpowder and beer
我都不记得上次洗澡是什么时候了
and I don't remember my last shower.
你能不能  给
Can you just... here.
给醒着的人买早饭  好吗
Whoever's still awake, buy them breakfast, okay?
告诉他们一切都会好起来的
Tell them everything's gonna be okay.
我要鸡蛋和...
I'll take anything with eggs and...
青椒  好的  先生
Green chilies, yes, sir.
天啊  你能去买吗
Jesus, can you just do it?
停车场
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
这是JGL吗
Uh, is this JGL?
你是谁
Who wants to know?
我是吉姆·克拉克  对他们的工作很感兴趣
Uh, I'm Jim Clark. I was interested in their work.
你来晚了
You're late.
真的吗
Really?
他们关门了
Yeah, they're out of business.
周五搬空的
Cleared out on Friday.
我们还在招人  如果你想来
We're hiring, though, if you're interested.
要值夜班  但很稳定
Lot of late shifts, but it's steady.
不必了  谢谢
No. Thanks anyway.
好吧
All right.
律师建议我们尽快起诉
Our lawyers advised us to sue immediately,
但我们还在考虑  看你们态度了
but we're holding off pending your cooperation.
那个数是我们两年来的所有开支
That number represents two years of our overhead
加上三倍损害赔偿
plus treble damages.
我跟你见面  仅仅是因为你们曾是我们的客户
I only took this meeting because, as a former client,
我觉得该跟你们解释清楚
I thought you deserved an explanation.
就像等人都死了
That's sort of like a ransom note
才索要赎金
after the victim's already dead.
不是死  是蜕变
I prefer transformed.
某些想法应该在更广阔的天地实现
Some ideas need a larger ecosystem.
给水牛大片田地  它就能茁壮成长
Give a buffalo a million acres, it thrives.
把它困在荒芜的小岛上  不出四代
Stick it on a desert island, in four generations,
-就跟小狗差不多大小了  -这故事很有趣
- it's the size of a poodle. - That's a charming anecdote,
但我来是有正事的  能好好谈吗
But I work for a living, so can we move this along, please?
-我们的行为不算侵权  -这些算法归我们所有
- We violated no copyrights. - We own proprietary algorithms...
你这是在乱编  承认吧
You were making it up as you went, at least admit it.
用私密社区联系用户...
Connecting subscribers in discreet communities...
你们那个功能别家也有  Delphi
The source does a version of that, Delphi,
-计算机服务  -我们没那样
- CompuServe. - Not like us.
我们有自己的东西
Not the same way as us.
这个想法属于它的原创者
This idea belongs to its originators.
要照你说的  可口可乐就还是止咳糖浆
If that were true, Coca-Cola would still be a cough syrup.
这个领域不喜欢抄袭的
This Community doesn't like copycats.
我们已经准备联系
We are prepared to reach
国内所有商业杂志
out to every trade magazine in the country,
每个关注科技发展的记者
every reporter on the tech beat.
比如《电脑杂志》的莱斯利·吴·弗里
Like Leslie Wu Foley from "PC magazine"?
里斯·詹金斯  约翰·克林齐
Reese Jenkins? John krinkey?
别放那么挤  伙计们
Not so close together, please, guys.
几个小时后他们都会坐在这儿  就是这儿
They'll all be sitting here, right here, in a few hours.
鉴于我几周前就发出了邀请
And since I invited them weeks ago,
他们会认为你是在眼红
I suspect they'll view your claims as sour grapes.
那我们就在旁边开发布会
We'll do a side-by-side.
但愿他们找得到穆特尼
If they can even find Mutiny.
顺便问问  你们准备什么时候重新上线
When are you guys going back up, by the way?
看看周围吧  唐娜
Look around, Donna.
我们今天就宣布
We're announcing today.
我们都准备好了
We're all in.
西方网络  在线
你打算坐在那儿跟我说什么
And you're gonna sit there and tell me what?
我该为你们让位
I should've nobly stepped aside,
看着你们蹦跶几年  苟延残喘
watched you guys flop around for years gasping for air,
挨家挨户兜售你们的小玩意  卖点小钱
shopping your little regional product door-to-door like thin mints?
-法庭见  -得了吧
- I'll see you in court. - Oh, come on.
我们都清楚这不可能
We both know that's not gonna happen.
很遗憾没帮上忙
Sorry we couldn't help each other out.
跟乔·麦克米伦联手可没有好下场
Holding hands with Joe Macmillan never ends well.
相信我  我清楚
Trust me, I know.
你怎么会认为乔跟此事有关呢
What makes you think Joe had anything to do with this?
逗我呢
You gotta be kidding me.
我知道新书写什么了
I think I found my book idea.
上了飞机我就把框架写出来
I'm gonna start outlining it on the plane.
-不错啊  写什么  -你啊
- That's great. What's it about? - You.
当然不是你这一个人
No, not you individually.
是讲适应现代生活的代价
It's more like the price of adaptation on modern life.
各种转型  痛苦
You know, transformation, pain.
你又嗑嗨了吧
How many of those pills have you taken?
没  我说真的
No, seriously.
创造性的破坏
Creative disruption, you know?
你惹别人不开心  但干大事的人都那样
You upset people, but so does anybody who rocks the boat.
同时你也创造了独特的东西
But you also gave birth to some pretty special things.
打一炮再上路
I'm taking one for the road.
搬家工人3点才来
The movers don't get here till 3:00.
乔
Joe.
我可以进去吗
May I?
-爸爸  -宝贝
- Dad. - Hey, sunshine.
抱歉  我邋邋遢遢的
I'm sorry, I'm a mess.
胡说  你这样就很好
Oh, nonsense. You look terrific.
我只是来祝你们一路顺风
I just wanted to wish the happy couple n voyage.
那么
So...
要去西部了  年轻人
go west, young man.
那里前景很广阔呢
Still a wide-open business.
说不定能发展大好  另辟蹊径
Do well, blaze a trail, who knows?
或许西方集团哪天会在那儿开分公司呢
Maybe Westgroup will open an office out there someday.
肯定可以
I have no doubt.
爸  这个真漂亮
Dad, this is beautiful.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你一定会喜欢那里的
Oh, you're gonna love it out there.
那是重新来过之地
It's the land of second chances.
乔  能单独聊聊吗
Joe, may I have a word?
-再见  亲爱的  -再见
- Bye, sweetheart. - Bye.
你不会真以为这套说辞就能封我的口吧
You didn't seriously think that bullshit would buy my silence?
当然
No.
你太意气用事  不会就这么罢休
You're far too emotional for that.
你盗取了别人的知识产权
You stole intellectual property.
事实上  我是先想花钱买的
Actually, I tried to buy it.
而且我记得  开价还不低
A very generous offer, as I recall.
只是那交易不知怎么出了问题
Only the deal went south somehow.
没必要拐弯抹角  是我背着你拆台
No need to dance. I went behind your back.
我建议穆特尼不要卖而且我不后悔
I told Mutiny not to sell and I'm glad.
我对你的看法真是一点没错
Every instinct I had about you was correct,
只是我没看出你会这么卑鄙
except how low you'd stoop.
-说完了吧  -还没呢
- We're done. - Are we?
如果我把此事公诸于众呢
What if I went public?
我是你女婿
I'm your son-in-law.
只要我说对一句话  你的股票就万劫不复了
I string together the right 10 words, your stock's in the toilet.
你不会这么做的
You don't want to do that.
你知道那样的话你想再重新来过会有多难吗
Do you have any idea how hard it's gonna be for you to start over?
没有西方集团  你的简历就是黑历史
Without Westgroup, your resume reads like a rap sheet.
我愿意一试
I'll try my luck.
那莎拉呢  你这么做对她会有多大影响
And Sara? How would your little stunt affect her?
积怨没好处的
There's no upside to grudges.
今天下午来参加股东大会吧
Come to our shareholders' meeting this afternoon.
指望我为你担保
The day I vouch for you...
今天会来很多大人物
There'll be a lot of very important people there.
能影响你未来的大人物
People who can make a difference to your future.
莎拉也会高兴的
Sara will be delighted.
我们可以像朋友那样分别
And we can part friends.
我们不是朋友  是亲人
We're not friends. We're family.
我们每隔一年圣诞节都会见面
We'll see each other at christmas every other year.
我们隔着屋子点头示意
We'll nod to each other across the room,
虚情假意地聊上三刻钟
and after about 45 minutes of fake chit chat and eggnog,
我就找个借口  抱歉还有事  先走了
I'll make an excuse. "We have to be somewhere. I'm so sorry."
等我的孩子问我
And when my children ask me
窗户里那个灰发的陌生人是谁时
who that tall gray stranger in the window is,
我就说一声  那是你外公
I'll remind them, "That's your grandpa."
下午见
I'll see you there.
不  不是双人射击
Oh, no, it's not a two-person shooter,
是双视角射击  所以
it's a two-perspective shooter, so it's--
不  我们确实不兼容那个平台
No, we're not compatible with that platform.
好吧  没有  感谢您抽时间
Okay, no, thank you for your time.
再见
Bye.
别来那套了
Hey, cut that out.
什么啊
What?
那副丧气的样子
That down-in-the-mouth crap.
行了  买家听到沮丧的口气
Come on, buyers hear defeat,
肯定退避三舍
they scatter quicker than crawfish at a church boil.
你可是强硬派老大
You're the boss bitch around here.
你是埃及艳后  裙下还有个大金矿
Queen of the nile. Sittin' on a gold mine.
能进来是他们的荣幸才对  懂吗
People be lucky you don't charge admission, get me?
西装笔挺的啊
You look sharp.
那是什么
What's that?
这是...
Oh, this is...
我们的新界面
Our next interface.
看到这些快速链接框了吗
See these quick link boxes?
能将用户跳转到他们感兴趣的内容
They'll kick users right over to their favorite area.
我已经开始写代码了
I've already started coding it.
抱歉  你有话对我说吗
I'm sorry, did you want to talk to me about something?
没  没什么大事
No, nothing important.
-先生  -你好
- Sir? - Oh, yeah, hey.
我在...找我的车
I'm just, uh, looking for my car.
先生  这里仅限员工通行
Sir, this area is for employees only.
没有通行证你不能进来
You can't get in without a pass.
-你有通行证吗  -没有  我...
- Do you have a pass? - No, I, uh...
你记得你停在几楼吗
Do you remember what level you were on?
我没太注意
I wasn't really paying attention.
-也许是五楼  -这儿没有五楼
- Maybe 5F? - There is no 5F.
这里是地下一层西区
This is basement level west.
也许你看见的是东  你停在东五区了吗
Maybe it was an E you saw. Did you park in 5 East?
也许吧
Maybe that's it.
楼梯在那边
Stairwell's right up there.
先生
Sir?
-你没事吧  -没事  没事
- You okay? - Yeah, yeah.
我很好  谢谢
I'm fine, thanks.
这些人是谁
Who are these people?
我打了将近一百通电话
Out of, like, 100 cold calls,
他们是唯一回电话的
they're the ones that called back.
听说他们只成立了几周
Word is they're just a few weeks old.
是啊
Yeah.
西方集团没让步喽
So Westgroup didn't back down?
没  那混蛋对我们的和解协议嗤之以鼻
No, the creep practically blew his nose in our settlement offer.
乔怎么说的
What did Joe say?
他没在
He wasn't there.
我觉得乔不知道西方网络的事
I don't think Joe knew about Westnet.
我觉得也许他说的是真话
I think maybe he was telling us the truth.
好了  可以进来了
Okay, we're ready for you.
实际上  伙计们  今天在这边谈
Oh, actually, guys, we're in here today.
好吧  走吧
Okay, well, here we go.
也许你该去的
Maybe you should go.
去股东大会吗
To the shareholders' meeting?
是啊  他不会料到你会去
Yeah, I mean, he'd never expect it.
他觉得你太骄傲
He thinks you're too proud.
但是想想看
But think about it.
你去参会  站在大家面前
You know, you go there in front of everyone.
让他们知道那是你促成的  你的主意
Let them see that it started with you, your vision.
从这场失败中捞到点好处
Just try and pull something good out of this fiasco.
然后我们把这一切都抛下
Then we can just leave it all behind.
一刀两断
Make a clean break.
你看着办
Look, it's up to you.
无论你怎么做  我都支持你
I'll be by your side either way.
游戏一半内容是间谍主题
So, half the game is a spy thriller.
你的任务是渗透进苏联监狱
Your mission is to infiltrate the soviet prison
拯救挨饿的异见人士  或者...
and rescue the starving dissident or...
你也可以扮演一名克格勃狱卒
You're an elite KGB prison guard.
你的任务是在美国人带着囚犯逃走前
Your orders-- find and shoot the American
找到并杀死他
before he escapes with your prisoner.
每一关都可以选择扮演渗透方或者营救方
So each level can be played as either hide or seek.
打破我们对于冷战的偏见
While totally scrambling our cold war preconceptions.
嗯  就像《高尔基公园》混搭《天狐入侵》
Right, it's like "Gorky Park" meets "Red Dawn."
前提是我们可以移植代码
If we can port the code.
图像方面  它没有理由
Graphically, there's no reason
不能在卡带主机上运行
it can't run off a cartridge.
但如果不是双人玩家
But without the live two-player aspect,
-它不就是个监狱版《战区》吗  -不
- isn't it just "Battlezone" in a prison? - No.
不  我们认为游戏的紧张感
No, we like to think that the tension
和幽闭感使它区别于其他游戏
and the claustrophobia really set it apart.
酷  太酷了
Cool. It's definitely cool.
布莱斯  泡几杯咖啡
Bryce, a couple of coffees?
稍等  伙计们
Um, one second, guys.
-借过一下  -好的
- I gotta just go that way. - Oh, sure.
概念上说  你们的东西很棒
Look, conceptually, it's really strong.
只可惜我们付不起你们的开发成本
I just wish we could cover your development costs.
你们的报价  超出我们的承受范围了
What you're asking, it's kind of out of our price range.
这个...
well, uh...
轻松一刻游戏公司
Funtime Games.
我觉得我们应该离开这里
Look, I think we should just get out of here.
先等等
Sit tight.
几位好
Hey there.
我是约翰·博斯沃思  来自穆特尼
John Bosworth, Mutiny, inc.
布莱斯  能让我们单独谈谈吗
Bryce, could you excuse us?
我看看
Let's see.
你们的总部在雷蒙德[华盛顿州]啊
Looks like you're headquartered up in Redmond.
这是什么  销售网吗
What is this? Distribution network?
-那是机密  -覆盖全国呐
- That's confidential. - That's nationwide, mm-mm.
背后金主肯定不小
Gents must have some serious backers.
博斯沃思先生  我得...
Mr. Bosworth, I'm gonna have to insist--
我完全不想
Oh, hell, I got no interest
搞砸你们的宏伟计划  无论是什么
in blowin' your grand plans, whatever they are.
这是个自由的国家嘛
Yeah, it's a free country.
但有几件事想说
Couple things, though.
首先  你们没必要冷落我们
One, well, there ain't no need to cold-room us
让一个菜鸟来跟我们压价
with the toddlers just to drive down our price.
我们是讲道理的人
Hell, we're reasonable people.
第二  在友邦旗帜下
Two, it's a lot easier to
建立滩头堡要容易得多
establish a beachhead under a friendly flag.
你们觉得丰田为什么
Why do you think Toyota's
现在要在菲蒙市造汽车而不是在富士什么地方
building cars in Fremont rather than Fuji-what-now?
原因就四个字  美国制造
Well, four little words-- made in the U.S.A.
你们的合伙人  如果他们推出的产品
Your partners, say they land their product
全装着日本游戏
with strictly Japanese games--
他们雇你们重新命名包装
ones they hire you to retitle and repackage--
听起来有点鬼鬼祟祟  是吧
Man, that sounds kind of sneaky, huh?
有点像入侵
Kind of like an invasion.
可如果他们搭载点当地的东西
But say they ship some homegrown titles,
美国开发的东西
ones they developed on these shores.
那就皆大欢喜了
Boy, that's kumbaya time.
把手伸过大洋
Hands across the ocean.
就算只为公关价值也该买
Might be worth acquiring for the pr value alone.
而且  还显得你们聪明  时尚
Hell, it'll also make you look smart, out ahead of the curve.
听听我们要说的
Hear us out.
你们不会后悔的
You ain't gonna regret it.
我们卖掉了
We sold it.
那下一步怎么办  他们什么时候付钱
So, then, what's next? When do we get paid?
-谁买的  -多少钱
- Who made the purchase? - How much?
-5万  -5万
- 50 grand. - 50 grand?
足够雇家新网络了
Enough to hire a new network
我们还会发一轮工资
and we will make payroll.
-穆特尼  穆特尼  -干什么
- Mutiny! Mutiny! - What?
-穆特尼  穆特尼  -好吧
- Mutiny! Mutiny! - Okay, okay, okay.
穆特尼  穆特尼
Mutiny! Mutiny!
天啊
Jesus.
有人吗
Hello!
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thanks.
肯定很难过吧
Must've been hard, right?
其实没有
No, actually.
我感觉轻松了
I feel lighter.
比之前一段时间思路清晰多了
I feel clearer than I've been in a while.
那是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
公司想要成功  我就得百分百专注
Look, if this company's gonna survive, it needs me 100% focused.
-我们之间的事...  -你是说咱俩的关系
- What we've been doing-- - You mean our relationship?
对
Yeah.
我太过满足  幸福了
I got too complacent and happy.
我放下了防卫  导致我们受了损失
I let my guard down and it cost us.
幸福不是什么副作用
Happiness is not some side effect.
-它是人生的全部意义  -好吧
- It's kind of the whole point. - Okay.
我不是在怪你
I'm not blaming you.
我是在承担责任
I'm taking responsibility.
这是我造成的
I made this happen.
其实  我觉得这是乔造成的
Actually, I think Joe is making this happen,
我觉得你就是翻不过篇
and I think you can't get over it.
或许你一直都没有
Maybe you never have.
你利用了我
You used me.
你让我相信了我们所做的事
You made me believe in what we were doing here.
知道吗
You know...
你比自己想的更像他
You're a lot more like him than you think.
可以让我单独待会儿吗
Do you mind?
需要帮忙吗
Need help with that?
这是技术活儿
It's technical.
在董事会面前做主讲
Keynote in front of the board,
好个结婚礼物
that's quite the wedding gift.
帮帮忙  自己滚下台  省得我把你丢下去
Do me a favor, get off the stage before I throw you off.
对了  有个记者找你
By the way, a reporter wants a word with you.
说是你的老朋友
She says she's an old friend.
你是来当着几百人羞辱我的吗
I assume you're here to humiliate me in front of hundreds of people?
真想啊
Tempting.
但是不  这已经没必要了
But, no, I guess that's no longer necessary.
是啊  我要走了
Yeah. I'm done.
我的生活一完蛋
I guess when my life goes up in a mushroom cloud,
我就会自然而然认为是你干的
I just naturally assume you're behind it somehow.
习惯了嘛
Old habits.
你要走了
You leaving town?
是啊
That's right.
跟你未婚妻吗
With your fiancée?
其实  我们已经结婚了
Wife, actually.
去加州本来是我的主意
Going to California was my idea.
记得吗
Remember?
在计算机分销商展览上
At comdex.
我差点被你说动了
You almost convinced me.
有个跟我亲近的人说  你依然在我的生活中
Someone close to me said that there must be a reason
这一定是有原因的
why you're still a part of my life.
你想过吗
Do you ever wonder?
如果
I mean, what if
我们不是
instead of
分开执迷地追逐
chasing what each of us wanted
各自想要的东西
separately and obsessively...
而是抓住彼此会怎样
We just held on to each other instead?
我知道你没抄袭我们的界面
I know you didn't copy our interface.
我知道那事不怪你
I know it wasn't your fault.
我希望你走前能听到我说这话
I didn't want you to leave without hearing that.
还有
And...
我一定是完全疯了  因为我心里有一部分
I must be totally mental, because part of me
根本不希望你走
doesn't want you to go away at all.
你根本不知道
You have no idea...
卡梅伦  我不能这样
Cameron, I can't do this.
不
No.
你是乔·麦克米伦  你想做什么都行
You're Joe MacMillan. I think you can do whatever you want.
对不起
Sorry.
给
Here.
这是我们原本的打算
That's what it could've been.
-再最后过一次  -好  稍等
- One last run-through? - Yeah, just a sec.
穆特尼
致乔  永远的  卡
好  走吧
Okay, let's go.
西方集团能源
年度股东大会
欢迎
Welcome.
很高兴见到大家
It's wonderful to see you all here.
希望大家都
I hope you all got a chance
看过了我们的通信终端
to check out our communication terminals.
你们可能会问  "一家能源公司
Now you might ask, "Why is an energy company
为什么要鼓捣电脑"
messing around with computers?"
我想向大家介绍
I want to introduce you to
构想了这个伟大策略的人
the man who conceived of our grand strategy,
他的热情甚至说动了我这样顽固的老古董
whose passion convinced even a stubborn old fossil like me.
有请我女婿  乔·麦克米伦  乔
My son-in-law, Joe MacMillan. Joe?
从洞穴画到幽默专栏
From the cave paintings to the funny pages,
石碑到电话
the stone tablets to the telephone,
我们人类寻求并渴望交流
we humans seek, we crave connection.
交流我们的各种想法
The exchange of our thoughts and ideas
从琐事到崇高思想
from the trivial to the sublime.
向大家介绍未来的
Welcome to the printing press,
出版物  报纸  和电话
the newspaper, and telephone of tomorrow.
只需在电脑上轻敲几下
With just a few keystrokes on a pc,
便可跟国家另一头的亲友说话
talk to loved ones across the country.
分享股票经验  说说故事  讲讲笑话
Share a stock tip, a story, tell a joke.
或者更妙  交新朋友
Or, better yet, find new friends.
找到志同道合之人
People who share your interests...
音乐  政治  电影  体育
Music, politics, movies, sports.
随时开启全天候的对话
It's a never-ending conversation on tap 24/7.
没有界限  没有边界
No boundaries, no borders.
这是通往新世界的道路
It's a pathway to a new world.
当然  关键就在于独特的界面
The key, of course, is the unique interface.
让参与不仅有趣
It makes participation not just fun,
不仅刺激  更让人上瘾
not just exciting, but addictive.
这一切
And all this...
All this...
这一切都始于一个很有才华的
This all began with a very talented
青年程序员  卡梅伦·豪伊
young programmer named Cameron Howe.
她看到了未来  先到一步
She saw the future and she got there first.
这不是我建造的  不是我所有的
I didn't build this. I don't own it,
它也不属于这里任何人
and neither does anyone here.
如果我们对此一笔带过  我们就是在摧残
If we skate past that, we're doing violence to the one thing,
这行或许唯一神圣的东西  原创性
maybe the only sacred thing in our business... innovation.
卡梅伦今天不能到场
Cameron couldn't be here today,
但她的天才却无处不在
but her genius is all around us.
我相信  在今后几年中都会如此
And will be, I suspect, for years to come.
谢谢  乔
Thank you, Joe.
谢谢
Thank you.
等等
Hey, wait!
停车
Hey, stop!
Stop!
停车
撑住  伙计
Hang on, buddy.
装备在这里架不起来  天花板太低了
Couldn't fit the rig in here. The roof's too low.
我们会给你处理好的
But we'll get you sorted.
我的车
My car.
那是我的车
That... my car.
That was my car.
那是我的车
That is my... my car.
我的车
My car.
脚踝别乱动  好吗
You want to keep that ankle stable, okay?
尽量别动
So try not to move too much.
很快就到了
Gonna be there before you know it.
谢谢大家
Thank you, everyone.
事实上  我们有自己的
The truth is, of course, that we have our own
-十分敬业的优质团队  -杰西
- dedicated and highly qualified team... - Jesse?
-日以继夜地...  -这正常吗
- ...Working night and day... - is this supposed to, uh...
稍等
One second.
我们还在修整一些...
We're still working out some of the...
杰西  怎么回事
Jesse, what the hell's happening?
-我不知道  -什么叫你不知道
- I don't know. - What do you mean, you don't know?
新增多个用户  索纳里斯检测到西方网络同时在线用户数
营救保卫战
做哨兵还是间谍
请进
Yeah, come in.
今天可真是的
Well, how's that for a day?
又绝处逢生了
Just pulled it out of our ass again.
真是不嫌烦呢
Never gets old.
是啊  但我们长教训了
Yeah. But we do.
我在考虑
I've been thinkin'.
或许我该离开这里了
It might be time for me to move on outta here.
嗯
Yeah.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
-你要辞职吗  -是的
- Are you quitting? - I'm afraid so.
我去面试了  看来他们是急着要人
I went for an interview, and, hell, I guess they're desperate.
你不能这样
You can't.
我们才刚刚站稳脚跟  我们赢了
We just got back on our feet. We won.
嗯  真希望我能说我期待
Yep, and I wish I could say I was looking forward
下次混战整晚的战役  但我
to the next all-night down-and-dirty scrap, but I...
我还能干多少年  五年吗
What've I got, five years left of my career?
至多十年
10, tops?
我得为家人找个安稳活儿
I gotta get something stable for my family.
我很快要有孙子了呢
Hell, soon my grandkids.
我会给你加薪
I'll give you a raise.
不是为了钱
It ain't about the money.
我老了
I'm just too damn old to
不能一日三餐都吃吐司
be eating three meals a day out of a toaster.
太没面子了
It's undignified.
多好玩啊
It's fun.
是啊  是挺好玩
Well, yeah. It has been.
如果我不接受你的辞职呢
Well, what if I don't accept your resignation?
如果你接受我才失望呢
It'd disappoint me if you did.
明天打给你
I'll call you tomorrow.
凯瑟琳
You know, Catherine...
睡会儿吧  亲爱的
Get some sleep, hon.
紧接着  我就掉下楼梯底了
The next thing you know, I'm at the bottom of a stairwell.
你昏过去了吗
So you blacked out?
大概是吧  我也不清楚
Maybe, I don't know.
我忘了时间
I just sort of lost track.
你也知道我的
I mean, you know how I get.
医生  我真是不好甩掉  是吧
Doc, like a bad penny, huh? Can't get rid of me.
要打个石膏吗
You gonna slap a cast on this thing,
然后放我出院
send me back out into the wild or what?
你拿到果汁了
Got your juice, I see.
嗯
Yep.
-跟你说句话  -好
- Just a moment? - Yeah.
抱歉  戈登告诉我他的病情在控制之中
I'm so sorry. Gordon told me his cte was under control.
是的  我们上周做过核磁共振
It is. We did an mri last week.
病情没有加重
The disease hasn't progressed.
那我就不懂了
Then I don't understand.
这次发作并非是病症
This episode was not symptomatic.
是心理问题
It was psychological.
他脱水  迷路了
He was dehydrated. He got lost.
迷路七小时吗  唐娜
For seven hours, Donna?
医护人员说他在救护车里崩溃了
The paramedics said that he broke down in the ambulance.
他跟你说了吗
Did he mention that to you?
重症确诊有时候会使潜在问题浮出水面
A serious diagnosis can sometimes bring out underlying problems.
戈登过去有过狂暴行为
Has Gordon ever experienced manic behavior
或偏执症吗
or paranoia in the past?
这么严重啊
That bad, huh?
那个
So...
你今晚恐怕不能回家了
I don't think you're gonna get to come home tonight.
赛摩尔医生认为  我也认同
Dr. Semel thinks, and I believe him,
情况可能不像我们说的那么简单
that this goes beyond what we talked about.
-他认为  -我知道
- He thinks... - I know, I know.
我需要帮助
I need help.
我被下了套  她给我搞了破坏
I was set up. She sabotaged me.
天呐  你听到自己在怎么解释了吗
Christ, can you even hear your own rationalizations anymore?
我受够了别人的怀疑
You know, I'm getting tired of being second-guessed
摆布和不信任
and manipulated and distrusted
我没做错任何事
when I have done absolutely nothing wrong.
我凭什么要相信你
Well, why should I believe a word you say?
因为你是我老婆
Because you're my goddamn wife!
我不管你对我爸做了什么
I don't care about what you did to my dad.
你俩就是一丘之貉
You two deserve each other.
而是你那么做的原因
It's why you did it.
这么久以来
All this time,
我以为你是受自己的天才所累
I thought that you were a victim of your genius,
是不被看好的预言者
some sidetracked prophet...
而我是你的第二次机会
and that I was your second chance.
但你不是  对吗  乔
But you're not, are you, Joe?
你就是个意外
You're an accident.
你是别人不该遭遇的不幸
You're something that happens to people who deserve better.
我不是个意外
I'm not an accident.
我该拥有更好的
I deserve better.
我该拥有你
I deserve you.
我真希望你知道这是什么感觉
I just wish that you knew what this felt like.
希望你能看到你说出她名字时自己的脸
That you could just see your face when you say her name.
说啊  乔
Say it, Joe.
说卡梅伦
Say Cameron.
天呐  你太迷失了
God, you're lost.
我们要你们能拿出来的一切
We'll take anything you can give us...
编程笔记  各关卡布局
programming notes, level layouts.
嗯  我都打包
Yeah, okay, I'll pack it up
明天叫人送去
and have someone drop it off tomorrow.
谢了  我知道放弃自己的孩子不容易
Thanks. I know it's not easy letting go of your baby.
嗯  你们怎么打算的
Yeah, so what's your plan?
你们找到发布平台了吗
Did you guys find a platform to launch it on?
嗯  我们有人选了
Yeah, I think we've got someone in mind.
但名字估计得改
Probably have to change the name, though.
《营救保卫战》  这是你还是汤姆的主意啊
"Extract & defend," Was that your idea or Tom's?
-什么  -汤姆·兰顿  他好有才
- What? - Tom Rendon. He's so talented.
我们还想挖他的墙角
Tried to poach him from you guys,
但他说他更想单飞
but he said he'd rather go it alone.
你看过他克隆的《视差》吧
You've seen his "Parallax" clone, right?
太有才了
Genius.
你认识他啊
Do you know him?
我们切磋交流好几年了
Yeah, we've been trading hacks for years.
你以为我们怎么知道你们的
How do you think we found out about you?
是他告诉我们的
He tipped us off.
我不肯跟你们见面简直就不放过我了
Practically broke my arm till I took the meeting.
喂
Hello?
你为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
有什么好说的  你已经拿定主意了
What was there to say? You already made your decision.
等等
Wait.
汤姆  站住
Tom, stop.
站住
Stop!
你会回来的
You'll come back.
你明早醒来
You'll wake up tomorrow morning
骑着你的破自行车过来
and you'll ride your stupid bike back here
我煮咖啡  你倒你的提子麦片
and I'll make coffee and you'll pour your raisin bran
我们再想个新东西出来
and we'll just come up with something new.
等等
Wait.
如果没有你  我是做不到的
I couldn't have done any of this without you!
不  卡梅伦
No, Cameron.
这事完全是你一个人做的
You did this all by yourself.